nielsenmedia.com 2011-12-05

# Nielsen | Privacy Policy

**Effective Date: September 15, 2010**

This privacy notice covers the collection and use of information for this website, <http://www.nielsen.com/us/en/> (“this website” or “we”). This website is owned by The Nielsen Company.

## About The Nielsen Company

The Nielsen Company (NYSE: NLSN) is a global information and measurement company with leading market positions in marketing and consumer information, television and other media measurement, online intelligence, mobile measurement, trade shows and related assets. The company has a presence in approximately 100 countries, with headquarters in New York, USA. For more information please visit [www.nielsen.com](http://www.nielsen.com/).

## What information we collect and how we use it

We ask those interested in obtaining more information about Nielsen's products and services to provide their names, email addresses, name of their company or website, telephone number and industry. Clients may gain access to their information through this site and may use a password or other means of authentication to do so. We do not sell this information to or share it with third parties, except as described below. We use your contact information to fulfill your request or respond to your inquiry, and may alert you to Nielsen reports, studies, Webinars or publications on related topics in which we think you may be interested. The emails that we send contain links that enable you to “unsubscribe” from future such mailings.

We ask those that seek a career at Nielsen to complete an application and provide related information. If you are interested in a career with us, please review our “Job Search Privacy Statement.” While it is consistent with this Notice, it contains additional information specifically for job applicants.

## Cookies and Web beacons

To keep track of your choice of language and home page preference, we place a cookie on your computer. A cookie is a small amount of data, which often includes an anonymous unique identifier, sent to your browser from a website's computers and stored on your computer's hard drive. Our “preference” cookie expires after thirty (30) days. We also use a small piece of code (sometimes referred to as “1x1 clear pixel,” “Web beacon” or “clear GIF”) placed in the pages of our website to help us gather additional information about which parts of the site receive the most visitors and other user traffic patterns, and enable us to administer the site. We also use cookies to understand your Internet usage, including other websites that you visit and, occasionally, your exposure to certain Internet advertisements as you surf the Web. To opt out of this explicitly, please [click here](http://server-us.imrworldwide.com/cgi-bin/o?oo=total&tu=http://www.netratings.com/privacy_opt.jsp?section=leg_opt%26opt=2). If you decide that you want your web surfing to be tracked, please [click here](http://server-us.imrworldwide.com/cgi-bin/o?oo=cancel&tu=http://www.netratings.com/privacy_opt.jsp?section=leg_opt). 

No personally-identifiable information is contained in our cookies or transmitted through our Web beacons.

You can set your browser to reject most cookies by following the browser help file directions. However, if your browser is set to reject cookies or you delete cookies, you may not be able to use some features of certain websites. You can also delete individual cookies or all cookies on your computer by following the browser help file directions.

## When we may disclose your information to others

From time to time, and notwithstanding any other provision of this Notice, we may partner with unaffiliated companies or individuals for market research product development or similar purposes. These companies or individuals may be provided with access to personally identifiable information, but we will require by contract that they agree to maintain the confidentiality, security and integrity of such information. We also may subcontract with other companies and individuals to do work on our behalf; they may be provided with access to personally identifiable information, but only as needed to perform their functions. Notwithstanding any other provision of this Notice, we may disclose personally identifiable information to any third party when disclosure is required by law, or desirable to permit us to exercise or preserve our legal rights or take action regarding potentially illegal activities or to protect the safety of any person. In the event that The Nielsen Company is acquired by or merged with a third party entity, or in the unlikely event of our bankruptcy, insolvency, reorganization, receivership, or assignment for the benefit of creditors, we reserve the right, in any of these circumstances, to transfer or assign the information we have collected as part of such merger, acquisition, sale, or other change of control.

## Children

This site is not directed at children under the age of 13 and does not knowingly collect any personally identifiable information from children under the age of 13. If a parent or guardian believes that this site has collected the personally-identifiable information of a child under the age of 13, please contact [nielsencookieoptout@nielsen.com](mailto:nielsencookieoptout@nielsen.com) and we will use our best efforts to remove the information from our records.

## Access to your information

You may contact us if at any time you would like to see the personally identifiable information we hold about you, or to ask us to correct or update this information, or to ask us to delete it.

## Data storage, transfers and security

We may store the personal details we hold about you for as long as needed, which may be indefinitely. We may store this information in the United States or we may transfer it to any other country. The data protection laws in countries to which personal data are transferred may or may not provide a level of protection equivalent to the laws in your home country. Wherever we hold the data, we will apply the terms of this Notice and any applicable data protection law. We maintain certain procedures to protect the confidentiality, security and integrity of personally identifiable information while it is controlled by us. However, the storage and communication of personal data cannot always be completely secure. Also, we cannot and do not guarantee that data transferred to third parties in accordance with this Notice will be protected against intentional or accidental misuse or loss.

Please contact us if you have questions or wish to take any action with respect to information to which this Notice applies. You can reach us by sending an email to [nielsencookieoptout@nielsen.com](mailto:nielsencookieoptout@nielsen.com).

## We may change this Notice and our data collection and management practices.

We reserve the right to update and make material and non-material changes to this Notice and to our practices in collecting and handling personally identifiable information. If we make material changes, we will notify you by email prior to their implementation and let you decide if you want the material changes to apply to your personally-identifiable information. We will also post a prominent notice at this website and indicate at the top of this statement when it was most recently updated.
